# Kishor Kumar Sridhar

645 Squaw Creek Drive, Unit 203, Ames, Iowa – 50010 | (515) 708-7091 | <u>kishorkumarsridhar@gmail.com</u> | <u>LinkedIn Portfolio</u>

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Graduate in Information Systems with 3+ years of industry experience in data analytics, data science, business intelligence, database management, stakeholder engagement, project management. Proven experience in statistical analysis, implementing Machine Learning frameworks, handling Big Data using HDFS, and presenting compelling dashboards to support evidence-based decision-making.

#### EDUCATION

Master of Information Systems, Minor in Statistics (STEM), Iowa State University, GPA – 3.75/4Dec 2020B.E. in Electrical and Electronics, Anna University, India, GPA – 7.58/10May 2013

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Programming:** Python - Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Statsmodels; R – tidyverse, ggplot2, leaflet; Git

**Databases:** MS – SQL Server, MySQL, MS-Access, Teradata, DB2, NoSQL - MongoDB

BI Tools: Power BI, Tableau, R Shiny, MS – Excel, DOMO, Alteryx, Looker Statistics: ANOVA, Hypothesis testing, MLE, Time series forecasting, A/B testing

Bigdata: Hadoop, Spark, Pig, Hive, MapReduce, Spark MLlib, GCP, AWS – S3, EC2, EMR

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Science Fellow May 2020 – Aug 2020

# Data Science for Public Good Fellowship, Ames, IA

- Led two Data Science projects to implement an end-to-end Data Science framework using statistical modeling and analyses
- Developed an R Shiny dashboard to improve public awareness of Iowa's resources related to mental and physical health, education, and childcare for evidence-based policymaking in substance abuse prevention, treatment, and recovery programs
- Performed data collection by web-scraping, built data pipelines, assessed data quality, and spatially mapped county-level composite indicators of Social and Natural Assets related to upward economic mobility
- Communicated data-driven insights to non-technical stakeholders using R Shiny dashboard to assess community well-being in Iowa
- Implemented time series forecasting to estimate alcohol sales in Iowa and spatially segmented counties under high-risk alcohol use
- Created a prototype of an interactive dashboard to perform sentiment analysis (NLP) by data mining transcripts from Hotlines to support improved customer service and auto-generate reports

Data Scientist Intern June 2018 – May 2020

# Iowa Department of Transportation, Ames, IA

- Implemented predictive models using FB Prophet in Python to estimate customer wait-times for Live display on DOT website
- Performed hypothesis testing, statistical modeling on pavement conditions and created Power BI dashboards to visualize insights
- Applied topic modeling (NLP) using LDA on 10,000 public feedbacks to identify factors governing highway maintenance in Iowa
- Used Python and Unix scripts to read and write large data sets on HDFS and analyzed high volume of data using Hadoop and Spark
  Worked with Hadoop clusters of 4TB size to analyze data using AWS EMR and reduced data storage by 75% using Parquet files
- Performed statistical analysis using MLlib in PySpark for identifying correlation between road crashes and weather conditions
- Terrorined statistical analysis using Nieno in Tyspank for identifying contribution between road crashes and weather conditions
- Improved the performance of application by 50% through Apache Spark ETL processes by transforming RDD to Spark DataFrames
- Developed efficient SQL scripts for data cleansing, transformation and data modeling for ad-hoc data analysis and reporting

**Data Analyst** Aug 2016 – Oct 2017

Torus, Chennai, India

- Automated insurance claims processing systems with integrated document management to reduce turn-around time by 30%
- Handled MongoDB database activities such as locking, transactions, indexes, Sharding, replication for advanced analytics
- Assisted in planning and implementation of experimental design for A/B testing to improve conversion rate based on various KPIs
- Analyzed data using efficient SQL queries; presented analytical findings, tracked metrics using data visualization in Tableau

Programmer Analyst Feb 2014 – July 2016

Infosys, Chennai, India

- Performed extensive data governance activities using Enablon EHS tool for a data migration project to modernize legacy systems
- Improved database performance by reducing query execution time by 50% using advanced SOL queries and stored procedures
- Communicated as a liaison between the client and technical team to deliver key business solutions using Agile methodologies
- Leveraged Microsoft SSIS to transform data for ETL processes; coordinated with QA teams to execute UAT cycles

#### **LEADERSHIP**